Finding Aid for Christina V. Pacosz diaries and publications, 1899-2011.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Christina V. Pacosz diaries and publications 1899-2011 1980-2004
Pacosz, Christina V.
2009116 Aa 2
Widely published American Polish poet whose life is at the heart of her poetry; diaries and publications.
7 linear feet in 7 boxes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Christina V. Pacosz (donor no. 10030 ) in 2008, 2010 and 2012.
Periodic additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Christina V. Pacosz was born and raised in Detroit, Michigan. Her parents were Sophia Anna Suchocka Kostrzewska and Walter Frank Pacosz. She began her writing as a child because of her parent's encouragement. Pacosz received her BS from Wayne State University in 1970. She taught school in Michigan for a few years, and then traveled westward where she taught special education in Estacada, Oregon. Wherever she taught, she also found time to write poetry. In 1986, she went on to study Polish and Jewish relations at the Jagiellonian University, in Krakow, Poland. During her career Pacosz has received several fellowships, awards and has been appointed as visiting artist at the Asheville Buncombe Technical Community College and the Central Piedmont Community College in Charlotte, N.C. In the early 1990s, she taught children with learning disabilities in Alaska. She eventually came to reside in Kansas City, Missouri. Christina V. Pacosz is an accomplished poet with a significant body of published and unpublished poems and prose.
This collection gives the researcher an insight into the works and mind of an American born Polish poet. It is divided into two series: Personal information and Published Works.
The Personal information series includes biographical materials, family records, correspondence, and personal diaries. The diaries contain a mixture of information such as the poet's dreams, to do lists, relationships, thoughts, poetry, daily life, travel and budgets.
The Published works series is divided into sub series, which include 2 Music scores, Web materials, Newspapers, CD and DVD Collection, Anthologies, and Works in Periodicals. The Anthologies are arranged chronologically and the periodicals are arranged alphabetically. Description of published works includes works available online via web sites not maintained by the University of Michigan. Web site links are valid as of December 10, 2012.
Subjects:
American poetry--Polish American authors.; Pacosz, Christina V.; Involuntary sterilization.; Polish-American poetry.; Polish American women--Michigan--Detroit.
Genre Terms:
CDs.; Diaries.; DVDs.
- Personal information
  - Biography (Box 1)
  - Family Records 1999-2012 (scattered)
    - Immigration Manifests and Description of Records 1899, 1907, 2012 (Box 1)
    - Janina Pacosz 1933, 1961 (Box 1)
    - Anthony Pacosz 1929, 1935 (Box 1)
    - Eva Holody Pacosz Miazga 1929-2000 (scattered) (Box 1)
    - Anthony and Mary Kostrzewski 1925-1972 (scattered) (Box 1)
    - Sophia Pacosz 1944-1993 (scattered) (Box 1)
    - Walter Pacosz 1927-1987 (scattered) (Box 1)
  - Olivet College High School Fine Arts Workshop 1963 (Box 1)
    (includes poetry by CP)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
  - Diaries
    (some with titles by Christina Pacosz)
    - 10/1971-7/1973 "In Michigan Teaching Croswell-Lexington, move to Portland" (Box 1)
    - 10/1973-11/1975 (Box 1)
    - 9/1978-1/1979 "Plains book Bus-Detroit, Plains Book Bus Saga Begins." (Box 1)
    - 1/1979-3/1979 "Plains Book Bus-Detroit, During layoff from Book Bus, based in Fargo, ND" (Box 1)
    - 1979 "Centrum, Port Townsend, WA Denise Levertov Workshop, with the Oregon poet, Ethel Fortner" (Box 1)
    - 12/1980-10/1981 (Box 1)
    - 10/1981-1/1982 (Box 1)
    - 1/1982-9/1982 "Dreams and Intimations" (Box 1)
    - 7/1981-5/1982 "Notes from the Red Zone begins here. PITS, Washington State" (Box 1)
    - 5/1982-10/1982 "Translation, notes" (Box 1)
    - 9/1982-4/1983 (Box 1)
    - 4/1983-9/1983 "Easter" (Box 1)
    - 9/1983-11/1983 "Poles/Slave Reb" (Box 1)
    - 11/1983-3/1984 "Hotel, short stories" (Box 1)
    - 12/1983-9/1986 (Box 2)
    - 3/1984-6/1984 "Hotel, short stories" (Box 2)
    - 6/1984-10/1984 (Box 2)
    - 10/1984-3/1985 (Box 2)
    - 3/1985-8/1985 (Box 2)
    - 9/1985-2/1986 "Move to Lancaster, S.C. I meet my husband, Larry Rollings" (Box 2)
    - 2/1986-7/1986 "Start of Journey to Poland" (Box 2)
    - 7/1986-8/1986 "Poland, this is not a place to sing, and notes for book" (Box 2)
    - 8/1986 Wegiel "Tours in Warsaw, at the home place in Poland, Orso" (Box 2)
    - 9/1986-2/1987 (Box 2)
    - 2/1987-9/1987 (Box 2)
    - 9/1987-2/1988 "Lancaster, S.C House fire, Papa dies" (Box 2)
    - 2/1988-8/1988 Haiti (Box 2)
    - 6/1988-2/1989 (Box 2)
    - 8/1988-1/1989 (Box 2)
    - 1/1989-3/1989 (Box 2)
    - 3/1989-8/1989 (Box 2)
    - 8/1989-11/1989 (Box 2)
    - 11/1989-3/1990 "Asheville, NC" (Box 2)
    - 3/1990-7/1990 (Box 2)
    - 8/1990-12/1990 (Box 2)
    - 12/1990-4/1991 (Box 2)
    - 4/1991-9/1991 "In Alaska!" (Box 2)
    - 9/1991-1/1992 "Delta Junction" (Box 3)
    - 1/1992-6/1992 "Delta Junction, Fairbanks, AK" (Box 3)
    - 6/1992-9/1992 (Box 3)
    - 9/1992-12/1992 (Box 3)
    - 12/1992-2/1993 "Myrtle Beach, SC" (Box 3)
    - 3/1993-7/1993 "Life." (Box 3)
    - 7/1993-11/1993 (Box 3)
    - 11/1993-2/1994 (Box 3)
    - 2/1994-6/1994 (Box 3)
    - 6/1994-1/1995 (Box 3)
    - 2/1995-5/1995 (Box 3)
    - 5/1995-12/1995 (Box 3)
    - 12/1995-5/1996 (Box 3)
    - 7/1996-9/1996 (Box 3)
    - 9/1996-1/1997 (Box 3)
    - 1/1997-5/1997 (Box 3)
    - 5/1997-12/1997 (Box 3)
    - 12/1997-6/1998 (Box 3)
    - 6/1998-11/1998 (Box 3)
    - 11/1988-5/1999 (Box 3)
    - 5/1999-6/1999 (Box 4)
    - 6/1999-8/1999 (Box 4)
    - 8/1999-1/2000 (Box 4)
    - 1/2000-3/2000 (Box 4)
    - 3/2000-6/2000 (Box 4)
    - 6/2000-9/2000 (Box 4)
    - 9/2000-1/2001 (Box 4)
    - 1/2001-5/2001 (Box 4)
    - 5/2001-9/2001 (Box 4)
    - 9/2001-12/2001 (Box 4)
    - 1/2002-4/2002 (Box 4)
    - 5/2002-9/2002 (Box 4)
    - 9/2002-12/2002 (Box 4)
    - 12/2002-3/2003 (Box 4)
    - May 2001 "Traveling in Iowa on way to Upper Peninsula to visit Doreen, Spring 2004 After Rick's death (CD)" (Box 4)
    - 3/2003-6/2003 "Invasion of Iraq" (Box 4)
    - 6/2003-9/2003 (Box 4)
    - 9/2003-2/2004 (Box 4)
    - 2/2004 (Box 4)
      (diary on CD)
    - 3/2004-10/2004 (Box 4)
- Published works
  - Musical scores
    - The Assumption, Three songs from "This is Not a Place to Sing" 1989 (Box 5)
    - From Alaska IV," Birch Trees Remember 1994 (Box 5)
  - Web poetry (Box 5)
    (with some prose, i.e. interviews)
  - Poetry and prose in newspapers and other serial publications, 2 folders
    - "Good Omens" and "The Last Spring Calf" The Changing Woman Vol.3, No.18, 11/1975 p. 4-5 (Box 5)
    - "A Great Deal of Doing: The Missouri Leadbelt Riot of 1917" Legerete, Issue 4, Fall, 1985 (Box 5)
      (Reprinting)
    - "It's the thought that Counts" Clinton St. Quarterly Vol. 7, No. 1, 1985 p. 18-19 (Box 5)
    - "The Root Word of Sad is Satisfy" The Arts Journal, March 1987 Vol. 12, No.6, p. 10 (Box 5)
    - "Down by the River " in No Picnic, 1988 (Box 5)
    - "A Solitary Goose in the Morning" 5 AM, 1993 (Box 5)
    - "Thoughts on Viewing the Plane in The Lake, Eielson Air Force Base, North Pole, Alaska" The Portland Alliance Vol, 21, No.1, 2001 (Box 5)
    - Fifth Estate
      - "A Gentle Rebuke To American Schoolchildren In the Form of a Poem." 1988-9: p. 14-15 (Box 5)
      - "Some Winded, Wild Beast" 1990 p. 26 (Box 5)
      - "A Commentary on Modern Existence as Noted by a Chicken on the Freeway near Columbia, South Carolina."1991 and 1999 (Box 5)
      - "Shoal Creek, Solstice 1999 p. 13 (Box 5)
    - Point, South Carolina's Independent Newsmonthly
      - "Erzulie of the Red Eye of Rage", Vol 5, No 60 1994 p 17 (Box 5)
      - "Francis Beidler Forest, Four Holes Swamp, South Carolina"; Alligator Moon", Harvest on the Shallotte River", Vol 3, No, 45 7/1993 p. 16 (Box 5)
      - "Standing at the Edge of the World", Vol. 5, No, 62 1994 p 19 (Box 5)
      - "A Woman Come to the Threshing Floor", Vol. 4, No. 47 9/1993 p. 15 (Box 5)
  - CD and DVD collection
    - This is not a Place to Sing 1987, 1 optical disks CDs (Box 5)
    - The Abundance of Mary, Songs and Poems in Honor of The Divine Feminine, 1 optical disks CDs (Box 5)
    - Montserrat Poetry Festival2010, 1 optical disks DVDs (Box 5)
    - New Works Review 2005, 1 optical disks CDs (Box 5)
    - The Night of The Arts, North Carolina Community College, Visiting Artists, Live at the Kennedy Center 1989, 1 optical disks CDs (Box 5)
    - "Writer as Spider" Telling Tales taped at Shelby, NC, Cleveland Community College, and other tapes 1988-1990, 1 optical disks CDs (Box 5)
  - Anthologies
    - Free from Dust, Neglect and Spiders' Webs, published by author in, while teaching at Estacada High School, Estacada, Oregon, original and only copy, including poems, 1974 (Box 5)
    - Shimmy Up to This Fine Mud, Poet's Warehouse, Portland, Oregon, 1976 (Box 5)
    - Notes from the Red Zone, The Seal Press, Seattle, Washington, 1983 (Box 5)
    - Some Winded, Wild Beast, Black & Red, Detroit, Michigan, 1985 (Box 5)
    - This Is Not a Place to Sing, West End Press, Albuquerque, New Mexico, 1987 (Box 5)
    - Greatest Hits 1975 --2001, Greatest Hits Series, #160 Pudding House Publications, 2002 (Box 5)
    - "One River," Issue 4, Winter/2007 Kate Bernadette Benedict, editor. New York. Appeared in One River, Pudding House, 2001 (Box 5)
  - Collaborative anthologies
    - "Kali," "Images at Bagby Hot Springs," "An Ear to the Earthquake," Hyperion, Black Sun, New Moon, Special Women's Issue, The Carolina Wren Press, Chapel Hills, North Carolina, 1980 (Box 5)
    - A Harvest of Unicorns," Rapunzel, Rapunzel, poems, prose, and photographs by women on the subject of hair, edited by Katharyn Machan Aal, McBooks, Ithaca, New York, 1980 (Box 5)
    - Mississippi Mud, Book of Days Calendar, "On Viewing Vishniac", 1983 (Box 5)
    - "To Leah," Perspectives on a Grafted Tree: Thoughts for those touched by adoption, compiled by Patricia Irwin Johnston, Perspectives Press, Indianapolis, Indiana, 1983 (Box 5)
    - Digging for Roots, Dalmo'ma 5, Works by Women of the North Olympic Peninsula, edited by Christina Pacosz and Susan Oliver, Empty Bowl, Port Townsend, Washington, 1985 (Box 5)
    - "Making Room for the Light," Digging for Roots Dalmo'ma 5, Works by Women of the North Olympic Peninsula, edited by Christina Pacosz and Susan Oliver, Empty Bowl, Port Townsend, Washington, 1985 (Box 5)
    - "The Seed Is the Light of the Earth," Looking for Home, Women Writing about Exile, edited by Deborah Keenan and Roseann Lloyd, Milkweed Editions, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1990 (Box 5)
    - Ovulation on the Summer Solstice," W omen of the 14th Moon: writings on menopause, edited by Dena Taylor and Amber Coverdale Sumrall, The Crossing Press, Freedom, California, 1991 (Box 5)
    - "Isis Again," A Gathering of Poets, edited by Maggie Anderson and Alex Gildzen, The Kent State University Press, Kent, Ohio, 1992 (Box 5)
    - "God In Her Infinite Wisdom Sends Crows," Fine China, Twenty Years of Earth's Daughters, Buffalo, New York, 1993 (Box 5)
    - "The Assumption of the Blessed Virgin Mary, August 15," reprinted from This Is Not a Place to Sing, West End, 1987 appeared in A Year in Poetry, edited by Thomas E. Foster and Elizabeth C. Guthrie, Crown, New York, NY, division of Random House, 1995 (Box 5)
    - "My Mother with Kohl on Her Eyes," Hard Love, writings on violence and intimacy, edited by Elizabeth Claman, Queen of Swords Press, Eugene, Oregon, 1997 (Box 5)
    - "On the Propensity of the Humans Species to Repeat Error," "A Message from the Past for the Present," reprinted from This Is Not a Place to sing, West End Press, 1987 appeared in Beyond Lament, Poets of the World Bearing Witness to the Holocaust, edited by Marguerite M. Striar, Northwestern University Press, Evanston, Illinois 1998 (Box 5)
    - "Shoal Creek, Solstice" reprinted in Fresh Water; Poems from the Rivers, Lakes, and Streams edited by Jennifer Bosveld, 2002 (Box 6)
    - "Unspeakable," Kritya: Poetry in Our Time, Volume 1/Part 2, Dr. Rati Saxena, editor. Kerala, India, July 2005 (Box 6)
    - "Weston Bend State Park, Weston Bend State Park, Weston Bend, Missouri," Jane's Stories III Women Writing Across Boundaries, edited by Glenda Bailey-Mershon and M. Eliza Hamilton Abegunde, Jane's Stories Press Foundation, Mt. Prospect, Illinois, 2006 (Box 6)
    - "Auschwitz: Oswiecim," Blood to Remember, American Poets on the Holocaust, revised, second edition, edited by Charles Ades Fishman, Time Being Books, St. Louis Missouri, 2007 (Box 6)
  - Works in Periodicals
    - "Four Gates to the City," Anima, Volume 11, No. 1, Chambersburg, Pennsylvania, Fall 1984 (Box 6)
    - "At Highland Hospital"and "Fort Yukon Alaska," Asheville Review -- Special Celtic Issue, 1995 (Box 6)
    - "Trying to Find out About Crazy Woman Creek, Wyoming" p56 Backbone, A journal of Women's Literature Volume 1, Number 2, 1985 (Box 6)
    - The Bellingham Review
      - "Angry Lament on 'Opening Day,' Draft Registration, July 21, 1980" and "A Neutral Morning," Vol. 4, No. 1, Spring 1981 (Box 6)
      - "God, in Her Infinite Wisdom, Sends Crows" and "Intimations," Vol. 6, No. 1, Spring 1983 (Box 6)
    - "This Time," Black Bear Review, Issue #11, Ave Jeanne, editor, Croydon, Pennsylvania, 1990 (Box 6)
    - "Out of the Corner," Blue Unicorn, Volume XVII, Number 2, Kensington, California, February 1994 (Box 6)
    - Poem on the Occasion of the Poet's Forty-third Birthday," First Place, The James Larkin Pearson Contest 1990 Bay Leaves, Number 20, The Poetry Council of North Carolina, 1988-1990 (Box 6)
    - Calyx
      - "Cheesecake,' Callouses & Veins," Calyx, a journal of art and literature by women, Corvallis, Oregon, February, 1978 (Box 6)
      - "Distances of the Heart," Calyx, a journal of art and literature by women, Corvallis, Oregon, October 1978 (Box 6)
      - Review by Leslie Hayertz of Notes from the Red Zone, The Seal Press, Seattle, WA 1983 appeared in Calyx, Volume 8, number 1, Fall, 1983 (Box 6)
      - "For a Small Girl Staring," Calyx, a journal of art and literature by women, Volume 13, Number 2, Corvallis, Oregon, Summer 1991 (Box 6)
      - Review of What Happened When the Hopi Hit New York, by Wendy Rose Calyx, a journal of art and literature by women, Volume 12, Number 1, Tenth anniversary issue, Corvallis, Oregon, Summer 1986 (Box 6)
    - "There Is the Geography of the Body to Consider," Catalyst, 3rd Erotica Collection, #17, edited by M. Kettner and Kathleen K., Laocoon Books, Seattle, Washington, 1988 (Box 6)
    - "Krakow Monument, Another View," reprinted from This Is Not a Place to Sing, West End, 1987 appears in Compages, Number 22, San Francisco, California, Fall 1989 (Box 6)
    - "The Geese and the Fox Who Was Too Late," The Charlotte Poetry Review, Vol. 3, No. 1, 1994-95 Series, Charlotte, North Carolina (Box 6)
    - "There Was No Moon," The Cream City Review, Special Poetry Issue, Volume 12, No. 2, Milwaukee, Wisconsin, Summer 1988 (Box 6)
    - The Devil's Millhopper
      - "The Poet Considers Exile," The Devil's Millhopper, University of South Carolina at Aiken, Aiken, South Carolina, Stephen Gardner, editor, 1989 (Box 6)
      - "Sophia Visits the Horse Islands," "Where the Earth Is Pregnant with Water," 1988 (Box 6)
    - "Copper Basin Hospital," Sing Heavenly Muse! women's poetry and prose, Earth, No. 19, Minneapolis, Minnesota, 1991 (Box 6)
    - What Is Offered," Earth's Daughters, #57, 2001 an earth odyssey, Buffalo, New York, 2001 (Box 6)
    - Earth's daughters index, issues 39-62 (Box 6)
    - "A Woman About to Give Birth Aboard Ship Speaks to Her Condition," Exquisite Corpse, A Journal of Books and Ideas, No. 39, edited by Andrei Codrescu, Baton Rouge, Louisiana, published by Illinois State University Publications Center, 1992 (Box 6)
    - "My Father Is an Old Man Dreaming," Part 3, Family Series," Living with Bounty," Ergo! The Bumbershoot Literary Magazine, Judith Roche, editor, Seattle, Washington, 1990 (Box 6)
    - "Near Big River," I-70 Review, Volume 3, Number 1, Lawrence, Kansas, 2006 (Box 6)
    - "Georgia O'Keeffe in South Carolina," published in Kaleidoscope of Carolina, A Journal of Writings by Women, Spring/Summer 1994 (Box 6)
    - Keystone
      - Judge for premiere issue of the Keystone, Central Piedmont Community College, Charlotte, North Carolina (student publication) while in residency as a North Carolina Visiting Artist, Fall, 1987 (Box 6)
      - "at first there is no clarity" p. 4; The Poet Contemplates the Violin p 29 1988 (Box 6)
    - "Leadwood," (essay) Legerete, Issue 4, Kimberly Coale Editor, Daphne, Alabama, Fall, 1985 (Box 6)
    - "Coker Creek, First and Last Place on Earth," The Lyricist, Volume XXI, Campbell University, Buies Creek, North Carolina, Spring 1987
      - "Premonition," The Midwest Quarterly, A Journal of Contemporary Thought, Volume XL, No. 4, Pittsburgh State University, Pittsburgh, Kansas, Summer 1999 (Box 6)
    - Moving Out
      - "The Black Madonna on the Hill of Light," modern folk tale from unpublished manuscript of same Opowiada n ia, Volume 13, Numbers 1 and 2, Detroit, Michigan, 1987 (Box 6)
      - "The Poet Considers Exile," "The Blueberry Day," Volume 14, Numbers 1 and 2 1989 (Box 6)
      - "Why Am I So Afraid," and "The World I Had Left Behind," short essays, from an unpublished manuscript Catholic Girl War Stories, Volume 15, Numbers 1 and 2, 1993 (Box 6)
      - "Butts Annie Been Walkin' on My Head," Volume 7, #2 8, #1, edited by Margaret Kaminski and Gloria Dyc, Detroit, Michigan 1979 (Box 6)
    - Now and Then
      - "The Writer as Spider," Now and Then, The Appalachian Magazine, Spring, 1992 (Box 6)
      - "Shooting at Snakes, aiming at Signs" 1994 (Box 6)
    - "Sophia Visits the Horse Islands," reprinted from The Devil's Millhopper in Outer Banks Magazine, Special 10th Anniversary Edition, annual, page 8 contributor's notes as well with author photo, Manteo, North Carolina, 1992-1993 (Box 6)
    - "Meditation on a Beaver Pelt," "An Ending," Outerbridge, Number 24, The College of Staten Island, Staten Island, New York, 1993 (Box 6)
    - "The Train that Never Came," The Peralta Press, Volume 1, Number 2, Oakland California, 2002 (Box 7)
    - "The Low-Rider, Trouble Machine," Permafrost, Volume 14, University of Alaska Fairbanks, Spring 1992 (Box 7)
    - "Anything You Say, Darling, Is Amen With Me," (epistolary literary nonfiction based on World War II era letters of poet's parents, Walter and Sophia Pacosz) Pig Iron, No. 17, The Epistolary Form and the Letter as Artifact, edited by Jim Villani, Youngstown, Ohio, 1991 (Box 7)
    - "Birch Trees Remember," "The Voice of Water: Winter," poetryALASKAwomen, Top of the World, Fairbanks, Alaska, 1993 (Box 7)
    - "Traveling With the Speed of Light," Poets On: Loss, Ruth Daigon, Editor, Mill Valley, California, Winter 1991 (Box 7)
    - "Francis Beidler Forest, Four Holes Swamp, South Carolina," "Alligator Moon," "Harvest on the Shalotte River," You, Year: New Poems By Point Poets, Volume 3, Number 45, Columbia, South Carolina, July 1993
      - Miscellaneous print-outs of poetry (Box 7)
    - "Isis Again," The Sow's Ear, Bristol, Tennessee. Partial list of contributors: Fred Chappell, Scot Owens, Eve Shelnutt, Spring, 1990 (Box 7)
    - "The Wind at the Wedding," reprinted from This Is Not a Place to Sing, West End, 1987 appears in St. Andrews Review, Issue No. 37, Laurinburg, North Carolina, 1989 (Box 7)
    - The Signal
      - "Doin' the Dinosaur Rag," "Dreamin' Dinosaurs," "Maiasaura Speaks," The Signal, Volume 1, Issue No. 1, David Chorlton, Joan Silva, co-editors, Emmett, Idaho, 1987 (Box 7)
      - "The Story of the Man Who Begged for Work (And How It Killed Him)," Volume 1, issue no. 2 The Signal, Emmett, Idaho, 1988 (Box 7)
    - "Can You Whitewash the Spirit," The Temple, Volume 5, #1, Charles Potts Editor, Walla Walla, Washington, 2001 (Box 7)
    - Brief review of Notes from the Red Zone, Third Lung Review, Number 3, Conover, North Carolina, 1988 (Box 7)
    - "Piety" (short story based on Thomas Wolfe's childhood) The Thomas Wolfe Review, Volume 16, Number 1, published by the Thomas Wolfe Society, Spring,1992 (Box 7)
    - "Trying to Find Out About Crazy Woman Creek, Wyoming," reprinted from Some Winded, Wild Beast, Black & Red, 1985 in The Witness, Volume 79, Number 4, Detroit, Michigan, April 1996 (Box 7)
    - "A New Broom Sweeps Clean," Kansas City Voices, a periodical of writing and art, Volume 5, Prairie Village, Kansas, 2007 (Box 7)
    - Liethua," modern folk tale from unpublished manuscript Opowiadania, appears on back cover of Woman of Power, Winter/Spring, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Anthologies and Works in Periodicals 2008-2009, 2011
    - "Celia Speaks" Conclave; A Journal of Character. Issue 1, 2008 (Box 7)
    - Qarrtsiluni, online literary magazine
      - "Depth of Field" in Journalling the Apocalypse, September-December 2008 (Box 7)
    - "Summer Is Fraying," Letters to the World, Poems from the Wom-Po LISTSERV, Red Hen, Los Angeles, 2008 (Box 7)
    - "For Rati in Kerala," Thatchwork, Delaware Valley Poets, Inc., 2009 (Box 7)
    - "Georgia O'Keeffe in South Carolina," Not a Muse; The Inner Lives of Women, a World Poetry Anthology, Edited by Kate Rogers, Viki Holmes, 2009 (Box 7)
    - "How is it a Satellite Photo of the Sea of Azov Appears in my Dreams?" and "In the Garden" from Waging Peace; a special publication of Voices [Education Project] to commemorate and celebrate The International Day of Peace 2009, September 21, 2009 (Box 7)
    - "For a Small Girl Staring2," Wait a Minute, I Have to Take Off My Bra, edited by Betty Dobson and Darcelle Adams-Frank, InkSpotter Publishing, 2011 (Box 7)
    - "I am My Own Velvet Painting," Connecticut River Review, edited by Lisa L. Siedlarz, Connecticut Poetry Society, West Hartford, Connecticut, 2011 (Box 7)
    - "Scattering the Ashes." Rhino 2011, edited by Ralph Hamilton, Rhino: The Poetry Forum, Inc., Evanston, Illinois, 2011 (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous on-line poetry (Box 7)
    - Anthology: Notes from the Red Zone. Number 1: The Seven Kitchens Press ReBound Series, 2009 (Box 7)
    - Various poems printed in the program to Second Annual West Side Detroit Historic Polish Church Pilgrimage April 18, 2009 (Box 7)
- Works published online
  (The URLs for the following online works were provided by the donor. Some may no longer be available.)
  - "A Bit of Tropic Outside the Delta Shop-Rite" Switched on Gutenberg: Volume 5, Issue No. 1, http://faculty.washington.edu/jnh/archive/vol5no1/tropic.htm
  - "Unspeakable," Kritya: Poetry in Our Time, http://www.kritya.in/02/en/poetry_at_our_time.html Volume 1/Part 2, July 2005.
  - "Can You Whitewash the Spirit?" from Greatest Hits 1975-2001 Pudding House, 2002 http://www.poetryrepairs.com/v06/028.html, 2006.
  - "Hunger," "December, Moon of Sacrifice," "The Lessons We Choose," "The Goose Girl Speaks," Passport Journal, Volume 10, January -- February -- March 2006. http://passportjournal.org/passportjournal.org/Pacosz/Pacosz_poems.html
  - "What Is Illuminated," "Dead Deer in a Ditch," "Deer in the Dark," http://www.northeastartskc.org/down0906/deerpoms.htm DownGo Sun, September 2006.
  - Edited essay by Farideh Hassenzadeh Mostafavi about Iranian poet, Nima Yushij and poetry translated by her, also with assistance from Christina Pacosz; posted on line at Jehat.Com http://www.jehat.com/Jehaat/en/Poets/Nima+Yushij.htm
  - "For Rati in Kerala" and "Letter from Haiti to the Dead," http://www.kritya.in/0211/En/poetry_at_our_time11.html April, 2007 Volume II/Part XI.